

## **EDUCATION**

READING MPHIL IN FISHERIES **SCIENCE** 

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (HONS) IN FISHERIES SCIENCE

University of Jaffna, Sri Lanka | 2016-2020

3.45/4; 86.25% GPA

## **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Computer Skills

**Work Planning** 

Leadership

Time Management

**Teamwork** 

Volunteer Working

Literature Works

### **CONTACT AT:**

No:55/9.8th Address: Cross.

Iruthayapuram west, Batticaloa

Email: uventhikka.ss8@gmail.com

Mobile: +94767166888

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Sri Lankan

Age: 30 Years

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/uventhikka-

sivanantham-0773a41b0

# **UVENTHIKKA SIVANANTHAM**

FACILITATOR | RESEARCHER

## **CAREER OVERVIEW**

While keeping my focus on my chosen course of study at the university of Jaffna in Biological Sciences and securing a second-class upper division Honours Special Degree in Fisheries science. I have also gained valuable life experience through actively taking part in a wide range of extracurricular community activities, successful research, community projects. My experience as an undergraduate and as a Demonstrator/ Assistant Lecturer in Fisheries in the Faculty of Science at the University of Jaffna. I am confident that I can face future life challenges including postgraduate education and research.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 – 2022: ASSISTANT LECTURER- UNIVERSITY OF JAFFNA. SRI LANKA

2020-2021: DEMONSTRATOR - UNIVERSITY OF JAFFNA, SRI LANKA

(Conducting lectures, practical session, experiments, tutorial sessions and providing technical / non-technical support in undergraduate course to fulfil specific learning objectives)

2014-2015: MANAGEMENT **ASSISTANT VIJAY** CONSTRUCTION & CO, BATTICALOA

(Maintaining files, assisting accounting works, and computing work in MS Office- word, Excel)

# **ACADEMIC EDUCATION & ACHIEVEMENTS**

2022 - Reading MPhil in Fisheries Science, University of Jaffna

2022 – Mobility Exchange Program under NOR-LANKA BLUE Project at UiT, Norway (Completed 30ECTS)

2016-2020 University of Jaffna, Sri Lanka- Bachelor of Science (Hons) in Fisheries Science Second Class Upper Division (GPA 3.45 out of 4; 86.25%)

2007-2011 Higher School Education: Vincent Girls' High School, Batticaloa, Sri Lanka.

- 2014- Completed Certificate in IT in British Computer Society (BCS) Higher Education Qualification, Provided by ESOFT METRO CAMPUS, Batticaloa, Sri Lanka
- 2014- Achieved Bronze Award of following E-Type, test IT private limited. bcs The Chartered Institute for IT.
- 2013 Awarded an Edexcel Assured Diploma in Information Technology with E-Commerce (International) with ESOFT Computer Studies Private Limited, Batticaloa, Sri Lanka.
- 2011- Obtained Ordinary Pass (S Grade) in general Information Technology Examination, Department of Examination, Sri Lanka.
- 2010- Certificate of Merit award in the Senior Division, Australian National Chemistry Quiz, ROYAL AUSTRALIAN CHEMICAL INSTITUTE.
- 2009 Certificate of Participation of Provincial Schools Educational Software Competition conducted jointly by Education for Knowledge Society Project of Ministry of Education and Microsoft Sri Lanka (Pvt) Limited.
- 2008- Certificate of participation in the Junior level, Australian National Chemistry Quiz, ROYAL AUSTRALIAN CHEMICAL INSTITUTE.
- 2008- Obtained Second Place in Group Singing of Provincial Schools level Tamil Day Competition
- 2006- Obtained Second division in First grade Music Examination, North Ceylon Oriental Music Society, Department of Education, Jaffna.

## PROJECTS AND AWARDS

- Kuganathan, S., Krishnamoorthy, S., **Sivanantham, U.** *et al.* First record of *Trichodesmium Erythraeum* Ehrenberg ex Gomont (Cyanobacteria) in the Coastal Waters of Kankesanthurai, Northern Sri Lanka. *Thalassas* (2023). https://doi.org/10.1007/s41208-023-00548-3
- S. Uventhikka, K.Sivashanthini, T.Thayalini, P. Jasotha and K. Velauthamurty (2023) "Proximate Composition and Mineral Composition of Fish Bone Powder of Siganus lineatus Collected from Waters Around Jaffna Peninsula, Sri Lanka", Sri Lankan Journal of Applied Sciences, 1(02), pp. 14–17.

Yoganathan Thapeetha, Kirisanth Saruga, **Sivanantham Uventhikka**, Krishnamoorthy Sivagini, Nadarajah Ragavan, Krishnapillai Nahmagal, Paramasivam Shobiya, Kuganathan Sivashanthini, Sathyaruban Sutharshiny (2022). "A study on mass accumulation of macrophytes in Northern and Eastern coast of Sri Lanka". 13th Asian Fisheries and Aquaculture Forum, Page 93-94

Sivarajah N, Irranious J A, Krishnamoorthy S, Kalaineethan T, Kugathasan D, Sivanantham U, Ketheesan N (2022) "Student initiated workshops: enhancing understanding of research in practice for undergraduates - a model for research training for developing nations in the post-pandemic world". 3rd ASI Education Special Interest Group Annual meeting, Page 14

*S.Uventhikka*, *K.Sivashanthini*, *T.Thayalini*, *P.Jasotha and K.Velauthamurty* (2021). "Quantifying Selected Nutritional Composition of *Siganus lineatus* Fish bone from Waters around Jaffna Peninsula, Sri Lanka", Proceeding of the 5<sup>th</sup> International Research Conference of Uva Wellassa University, IRCUWU2021, Page 47

*P. Shobiya, S. Uventhikka*, *K. Sivagini, A.M.H.D.Amarathunga, R. Gobykrishanth, A.S.R. Fernando, K.Sivashanthini*(2020). "Marketing channels and intermediaries in Gurunagar fish market, Jaffna, Sri Lanka", Proceeding of the 9<sup>th</sup> Annual Science Research Sessions of Southeastern University of Sri Lanka, ASRS2020. Page 4

Motivational workshop to Students and Parents, Career guidance workshops, Skill development workshops for kids, Library projects, Environmental conservation, and Women empowerment workshop Since 2017, War affected region, Northern Province, Sri Lanka. (Volunteered Manitham Projects)

## **CO- CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

2017-Present: Life member of MANITHAM Organization (Humanity)

(Manitham is non-governmental organization in Sri Lanka. Registration Number: NAL/DS/05/MAN/20/2018 established in 2016 by a group of students from University of Jaffna to work towards community to change the life of those who have no hope)

2020-2021: Treasurer of Fisheries Science Society of Department of Fisheries Science, University of Jaffna.

2019-2020: Student Representative of Center for Gender Equity and Equality (CGEE), University of Jaffna.

(Centre is functioning to co create a gender responsive environment and to integrate gender into the function of the University to attain gender equity, equality and gender empowerment)

2019-2020 Environmental conservation Project Manager of MANITHAM Charitable Organization.

2020- First Runner-up in the Group Singing, Faculty of Science, University of Jaffna

2020- Second Runner-up in the Solo Singing, Faculty of Science, University of Jaffna

2019- Youth Forum Panelist at the symposium on "Empowering Communities to Address Violence against Women and Girls" Organized by University of Jaffna and British Council, Sri Lanka.

2018- First place in the AQUA CRIK Cricket Tournament in Fisheries Science Society, University of Jaffna.

2018- Certificate of Photography Competition in Department of Fisheries Science, University of Jaffna.

2017- Certificate of Photography Competition in Department of Fisheries Science, University of Jaffna.

2014- Awarded this Certificate on Completion of Accelerated Skills Acquisition, USAID and The Ceylon Chamber of Commerce.

2006- Certificate of Participation in the Ceylinco Ran Daru Art Competition & Exhibition at the Sri Lanka Exhibition and Convention Centre

### COMPLETED COURSES AND ONLINE PROGRAMME

2022- 8 Days of Residential/ International workshop on "Perspectives in blue environment and socioeconomics" Organized by the University of Ruhuna, Matara, Sri Lanka under NOR-LANKA BLUE Project (April 4<sup>th</sup> -12<sup>th</sup>, 2022)

2021- National Webinar on "Empowering Women Through Entrepreneurship" organized by Guru Nanak Centre for Research (GNCR), Velachery, Chennai

- 2021- Certification of participation and completion of online certificate course held on Microbiology Techniques organized by Spectrum Institute of Science & Technology on 12<sup>th</sup> & 13<sup>th</sup> July 2021
- 2021- Webinar on "Marine Biodiversity and Conservation" organized by Fisheries Science Society in Collaboration with Department of Fisheries, University of Jaffna, Sri Lanka.
- 2021- Live Webinar on FISAT II organized by Fisheries Science Society in Collaboration with Department of Fisheries, University of Jaffna, Sri Lanka.
- 2020- Online Workshop on "PRIMER- THE STATISTICAL SOFTWARE THAT EMPOWER THE RESEARCHERS" organized by Guru Nanak Centre for Research (GNCR), in association with the Internal Quality Assurance Cell (IQAC) of Guru Nanak College, Velachery, Chennai
- 2020- Webinar on "Recent Advances in Marine Biodiversity and Conservation" organized by the Department of Oceanography and Coastal Ares Studies, Alagappa University, Tamilnadu, India (18.05.2020-20.05.2020)
- 2020- Completing the Online Course "Explore the Planet Earth" Organized by Octophin held on 1<sup>st</sup> to 6<sup>th</sup> December 2020
- 2020- An online non-credit course on Understanding Research Methods authorized by University of London and offered through Coursera.
- 2020- An online non-credit course on COVID-19: What You Need to Know (CME Eligible) authorized by Osmosis.org and offered through Coursera.
- 2020- An online non-credit course with Honors on Becoming a changemaker: Introduction to Social Innovation authorized by University of Cape Town and offered through Coursera.
- 2020- An online non-credit course on Successful Career Development authorized by University system of Georgia and offered through Coursera.
- 2017- One day Hands on Training on "Herpetology Amphibians" provided by Department of Zoology, University of Jaffna.

## REFEREES

Prof. (Mrs.) S. Kuganathan Head,
Department of Fisheries Science,
Faculty of Science,
University of Jaffna,
Srilanka.
sivashanthini@univ.jfn.ac.lk
0774006669

Mrs.T.Thileepan,
Senior Lecturer,
Unit of Siddha Medicine
University of Jaffna,
Srilanka.
Thayalini08@gmail.com
0770556790